GURUVENU KAMANURU

COBOL/MAINFRAME DEVELOPER

CONTACT

.

+49 176 239 73753

 \bowtie

guruvenu.k152@gmail.com



Bahnhofspassage2, Wolfsburg 38440

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/guruvenu-kamanuru-11n31a2152

.....

SKILLS

COBOL, JCL, CICS

DB2, IMSDB, VSAM

Power-BI, Excel, C and Python

SQL, SPUFI, Endevor, Fileaid, IBM debugger, Expeditor

EDUCATION

Master of Technology | Machine Design

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Ananthapur, India

2017 - 2020

Bachelor of Technology | Aeronautical Engineering

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Hyderabad, India

2011 - 2015

LANGUAGES

English - Proficient

German-Beginner level

PROFILE

Having 3+ years of experience on Mainframe Technologies. Capacity to function admirably in both Team and individual climate. Strong Knowledge on Analysis, Design, Coding, Testing, Implementation and complete SDLC process. Provided product support and performed maintenance and enhancement. Investigating everyday issues revealed by business clients. Created various mainframe ad-hoc and automation reports with the production data.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Developer

Galaxe Solutions, Hyderabad, India | CIGNA Healthcare

Nov 2022 - Jun 2024

- Project is based on US Healthcare business we handles the Polar Eligibility section which process Medicaid, Medicare and Commercial client data and generate the Reports as per client needs. Majorly we deal with the transmission Part of Mainframe generated data thru MFT, FTP, SFTP and AWS servers.
- Developed the Automated switch System in application for Data transmission and Data generation as per the client requirements.
- Design and Development of batch programs and jobs using COBOL, JCL, DB2, VSAM
- · Actively involved in learning the process with in the Applications
- Performing and validating QA test cases
- Preparing unit test case report, UATR, RTCR
- Debugging and implementing the system
- Involved in production support activities. Ensured the batch cycles get completed in time.
- Work involves in development, enhancements bug fixes and fixing abends.
 Involved in monitoring the deployed batch cycles.
- Analyzing modifications, finding affected list of elements and homogeneous implementation in case of emergencies.

Associate Developer

Cognizant Technologies, Chennai, India| Ford motors

June 2021 - Nov 2022

- Project manages Retail business to handle the transactions among Importers and exporters. It is support and upgrade project which is affected when new business is acquainted or with change the usefulness of existing plans.
- As part of the integrating efforts had extensive meetings with both the business and end users to gather requirements
- Analysis and understanding the requirements and functional specifications
- Conduct joint application development (JAD) to review the business document with in the team.
- of business end users, application developers and Technical Analysts
- Preparation of TSD (Technical Specification Document) based on existing functionality and Requirements
- Created detailed technical design specification for enhancing the batch programs, care was taken to reuse most of the existing components/modules.
- Development of new batch programs using COBOL, DB2, JCL and IMSDB
- Debugging and implementing the system using IBM Debug tools
- Involved in preparing test plans for independent unit testing and QA Testing

TOOLS

BA Tools: JIRA, Rally Microsoft tools: Word,

- PowerPoint, Excel
- Power-BI

Querying tools: DB-Visualizer,Data-Studio Z/OS Tools: SPUFI, IBM

- OnDemand, JENKINS,
- Endevor, FileAid
- ,FileMNGR, CA7,
- Expeditor, CICS explorer

VISA- Sponsership: Not Required Authorized to work in Germany/ Europe

WORK EXPERIENCE

Desktop Support Engineer

Net-connect Global, Bangalore, India | Societe Generale

Oct 2016 - Jul 2017

- Network admin, IP handling, remote access allocation and troubleshooting in both Software and Hardware
- Formatting newly allocated drives and servers. Data dispose and Destruction.
- Handling tickets in ITSM related to hardware, software and IP connectivity issues.

Trainee Engineer

TLE Technologies, Bangalore, India

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

- Network admin, IP handling, remote access allocation and troubleshooting in both Software and Hardware
- Formatting newly allocated drives and servers. Data dispose and Destruction.
- Handling tickets in ITSM related to hardware, software and IP connectivity issues.
- Documentation of inventory and IT store management.